DAVID COSTA

WEB DEVELOPMENT TECHNICIAN DEVELOPER FULLSTACK JAVA

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-costa-yafar/

Porfolio: https://davidcosta92.github.io/porfolio-david-costa/

david.costa.yafar@gmail.com

(264) 15 464 7572

Mendoza, Argentina



I have spent 7 years in health care and was an entrepreneur, but now I am seeking new challenges. I am a software development technician, continuously learning about specific technologies and creating freelance projects. I plan to continue my degree, but in the meantime, I would like to join a diverse and dynamic team where I can impact the world through technology! I believe in agile groups, where goals are shared and approached from various perspectives. I think of products in terms of value contribution, efficiency, scalability, dynamism, and constant adaptation.

EDUCATION

Technician Degree in Web Development and Digital Applications - ISPC

03/2022 - 06/2024

Programming fundamentals, algorithms, data structures, OOP, Architecture, Requirements analysis and documentation, user stories, acceptance criteria, planning, UML Design, SQL and NoSQL databases, Java, Python-Django, Android Development, Client-server, SOLID principles, clean architecture, Testing, Networks, Cybersecurity, versioning with Git, GitHub, Git Flow, Agile methodologies, Scrum, Kanban, Miro, Figma.

COURSES -----

Backend JAVA - SPRING - Folcademy / San Juan Tec / UTN / TodoCode

12/2021 - Present

Development, testing, and deployment of APIs using Java, Spring, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, Hibernate, Microservices, Spring Cloud, Rest Template, Feign, Eureka Server, Load Balancer, Resilience4j, API Gateway, Docker, Docker Hub, Postman, Swagger, Spring Security, JWT, Logging with Log4j, Mockito, Test Containers, Maven, Gradle, Jasper Reports, Thymeleaf, Git, Git Flow, GitHub, Railway, Bitbucket, among others.

SQL, Server Administration, Database Design - San Juan Tec / UTN / Coderhouse

08/2023 - 11/2023

Advanced SQL Language, MySQL, Backups, Functions, Triggers, Views, Stored procedures, Design and normalization.

Python - Django - Flask - ISPC, Cisco Academy

03/2023 - 11/2023

Language fundamentals, logic and algorithms, design and development of APIs, with relational databases. Git and GitHub

Full Stack React JS, Node JS, Mongo DB | Stack MERN - Coderhouse

01/2022 - 07/2023

React - Node Js, Express, Mongo, Mongoose, websockets, Docker, Kubernetes, Artillery, Unit and integration testing, Swagger, Firebase, REST API development and consumption. Promises, Documentation, Logging, Mailing, Third-party Authentication, JWT, among others.

LANGUAGE: Ingles nivel C2, Proficient EF SET Upper Intermediate

Skills: Continuous Learning - Teamwork - Leadership - Problem analysis and solution - Conflict resolution - Negotiation -Goal oriented - Self management - Assertive communication and empathy - Dynamism and flexibility - Planning

Software: Intellij, VS Code, Eclipse, Android Studio, Postman, MySql Workbench, PgAdmin, MongoDb, Db browser, Jaspersoft, Slack, Discord, Figma, Miro, Trello, Diagrams, vercel, render, railway, clever cloud, Spring initializer, among others.

EXPERIENCE -----

----- Portfolio Link 7

Backend developer JAVA - Donatello

Deploy [7] Repository [7] SaaS platform for small food businesses seeking intuitive and functional business management options. Developed an MVP to quickly validate the product. Created within an agile, self-managed, and diverse team, consisting of professionals in UX/UI, Frontend,

Backend, DevOps, and QA. I served as the Lead Backend, with responsibilities including:

Analyzing, developing, and documenting the REST API, using Java - Spring, Spring Security with JWT, Swagger, Feign.

- · Leading integration between teams, facilitating communication, negotiation, and moderation of changes or suggestions to be implemented across the project's different repositories, ensuring smooth communication and achieving a successful MVP.
- Conducting code reviews, presenting, and defending the project in various tracking meetings and at the final deliveru.

Fullstack developer JAVA - React Js, App Embarcadero

Deploy [7] Repository [7]

System for managing boats, guards, rescue teams at each dam in San Juan Province, allowing for the maintenance of records on boats accessing, assigned personnel, visitors, and other vital data for statistics and analysis. The project is currently in a development stage where the first MVP has been developed, and it is now in the feedback phase.

- . During this stage, the survey, analysis, and design of the proposed solution were carried out, along with its web coding and testing, using technologies such as: Java, Spring, MySQL, Swagger, Spring Security, JWT, Mockito, Email Sender, etc.
- The frontend was developed using React JS, Material UI, among others. Future iterations will include a mobile app for Android.



DAVID COSTA

WEB DEVELOPMENT TECHNICIAN DEVELOPER FULLSTACK JAVA

Developer Android - backend Java, One Drop - Web and Mobile Application

Repository 05/2022 - 06/2024

Website development done in Angular, Backend in Java Spring, and a mobile app in Android (Java), created to manage patient health records, accessible by healthcare staff. It handles glucose, weight, blood pressure records, and other analyses, primarily focused on diabetic patients. The project was developed in a Scrum team, where I took charge of leading the design and development of the backend, focusing on Java architecture, database design, and the logical functions of the Android application. My main tasks and roles were:

- · Scrum Master. Planning development tasks and estimating times and efforts to achieve the objectives of each sprint.
- Leading logical development in Android, researching and learning how to create requested functionalities, demonstrating great proactivity, adaptability, consistency, and resilience to develop new features.
- Development of REST API architecture, and implementation of its critical functionalities. Technical documentation with Swagger.
- · Contributing to the entire project documentation, requirements analysis, user stories, planning, among others.
- The MVP was completed with a high level of quality, exceeding expectations, and demonstrating the potential of the project, its possible impact, and economic viability

FullStack Developer JAVA - React Js, API RESTFul EduProject, JAM 2023

Repository 10/2023 - 12/2023

Aplicación web, para la gestión de inscripciones, asistencias y usuarios académicos, como parte del evento JAM 2023 para crear soluciones de software gratuitas para emprendedores. A partir de una problemática propuesta, se analizó posibles soluciones que llevaron a diseñar e implementar un MVP, que se desarrollo dentro de un equipo scrum formado por otros devs, UX/UIs y PO, en un proceso iterativo e incremental usando Java - Spring, MySQL, React Js, Swagger, Github, Figma, Notion, etc. Mi tareas fueron:

- Analizar problematica y en equipo proponer y presentar soluciones eficentes, para que el cliente elija.
- Diseñar, desarrollar y documentar backend con Java Spring, implementar seguridad con Spring Security usando JWT.
- Codificar frontend con React JS, siguiendo los lineamientos de diseño.
- Se cumplió el objetivo de entregar un rapido MVP, superando las expectativas y permitiendo validar la idea de negocio de forma economica y ayudando a gererar informacion de gran importancia para el cliente.

Front end Developer React JS - Mecantronic

Deploy 1/2023 - 04/2023

Web application for managing registrations, attendances, and academic users, as part of the JAM 2023 event aimed at creating free software solutions for entrepreneurs. Starting from a proposed problem, we analyzed possible solutions that led to designing and implementing an MVP, developed within a Scrum team composed of other developers, UX/UI designers, and product owner, in an iterative and incremental process using Java - Spring, MySQL, React JS, Swagger, GitHub, Figma, Notion, etc. My tasks were:

- Analyze the problem and, as a team, propose and present efficient solutions for the client to choose from.
- Design, develop, and document the backend with Java Spring, implement security with Spring Security using JWT.
- Code the frontend with React JS, following design guidelines.
- Achieved the goal of delivering a quick MVP, surpassing expectations, and enabling the validation of the business idea
 economically, while also generating valuable information for the client

OTHERS EXPERIENCIES -----

Entrepreneur - Hidropedales San Juan - Taibe

06/2018 - 12/2022

Tourism entrepreneurship, focused on adventure sports and with a gastronomic addition, offering innovative proposals in one of the main tourist spots of San Juan, aimed at boat rentals, event organization, and experiences that mix water and land sports, with discovery gastronomic activities. The entrepreneurship was made up of another partner and the staff, reaching a team of 14 people. My main tasks were:

- Team management, organization, and motivation. Conflict resolution and negotiation among peers. Selection, training, and onboarding of new collaborators. Creation of procedures, protocols, and work standards.
- Customer management and negotiation. Analysis, development, and implementation of new tourism proposals and events.
- · Administrative and accounting management of the entrepreneurship.